# 搞點象草給豬吃
I get some elephant grass for the pig.
# 你看 這象草都很嫩的 葉子又多
Look! The elephant grass here is all very young, with a lot of leaves too.
# 夠多
Plenty enough
# 這羊喜歡吃嫩草
These goats like young grass.
# 吃它都不吃
It's not eating at all.
# 聞一下 香不香
It's smelling. Is it good?
# 聞到了它這個味道
It now recognises the smell,
# 好吃的味道
a tasty smell.
# 要把鐵鏈把它拴起來 牽出去哦
I gotta tether it with the chain, and take it out.
# 不牽出來它一直待在這裡 沒有活動
Otherwise it's always staying here, without anything to do.
# 這豬 豬肉都不好吃
Then the pig, the pork won't taste good.
# 剛好帶個鏈子過來
It just so happens that I have a chain with me.
# 給你帶條金鏈子
I'm putting on a gold necklace for you.
# 它聞到甚麼好吃的了 走它都不走
It smells some good food, so it's not going.
# 走 到下面去 下面有好吃的
Let's go, go down there! There's very good food!
# 走 這裡沒甚麼好吃的
Go! You can't find good food here.
# 走 下面去 你看多乖 很聽話
Go! Go down there! Look! It behaves so well. It's a good boy.
# 把鏈子掙脫 掙脫鏈子我就那個 我就放出你來'
Break free the chain, break free the chain and then I'll, you know, I'll let you go out.
# 哎呦 你看 好聰明哦
Ayo! Look! It's so clever!
# 太聽明了它
It's far too clever.
# 現在你自由啦 放在這裡啊
You're free now. I'll leave you here, alright?
# 要不就明天把它宰了
Should I just kill it tomorrow?
# 來 摸一下你可以吧
Hey! May I touch you?
# 摸一下你可以吧
May I touch you?
# 哎呦 真乖
Ayo! Good boy!
# 這是那甚麼 肥肉是不是 那麼多肥肉
What is it? Is it fat? You have so much fat.
# 我喜歡吃瘦的
But I prefer lean meat.
# 摸一下 真是的
Let me touch you, c'mon!
# 你看 給你抓癢癢
Look! I'm rubbing you.
# 是不是很享受
You enjoy it, don't you?
# 是不是
Don't you?
# 不要跑啊 跑了之後我逮到你我就 直接磨刀啦
Don't try to run away! If I catch you running away, I'll be sharpening my knife right away.
# 先把你放出來自由活動一下
I let you come out and do whatever you like.
# 等一下自己回 回自己的窩裡面去啊
You go back, back to your own pigsty in a while, alright?
# 是不是很舒服
Do you feel great?
# 好乖啦現在
It's a very good boy now.
# 你看 是不是
Look! Isn't it?
# 對你多好 是不是
I treat you so well, right?
# 它肚子 誒呀
It's belly, eya!
# 現在好乖啦
It's a very good boy now.
# 看你這 臉上的肉 那麼多
Have a look at your face. It's so meaty.
# 你看
Look!
# 它在享受
It's enjoying.
# 想睡覺 呵呵 等下搞很它好像睡覺了
It wants to sleep! It might be enjoying so much that it looks like sleeping.
# 是不是 不要跑就行在這裡
Right? Stay here and don't run away. Then everything will be fine.
# 要跑了被我抓到了我就把你宰了
I'll kill you if I catch you running away.
# 可以了 不把你關到裡面去 你在這裡啊 跟鵝跟鴨在一起 (註︰只吃剩一隻鴨一隻鵝)
Alright! I'm not locking you up inside. You can stay here, together with the duck and the goose.
# 只要你聽話我就不吃你
I won't eat you as long as you're a good boy.
# 天天待在這裡 你把它吃胖一點
You can simply stay here every day. Eat more and grow fatter,
# 越胖越好
the fatter the better, okay?
# 最少 最少吃到三百斤去
Grow up to at least, at, at least a hundred and fifty kilograms.
# 長成兩百斤我就不宰你啦
I'm not killing if you reach up to a hundred kilograms.
# 嗯 要聽話哦 知不知道
Um! Be a good boy! Got it?
# 好啦 聽它在這裡睡大覺吧
Alright! Let it have a good and sound sleep here.
# 等下自己找吃的啊 我沒東西餵你哦
Make sure that you get something to feed yourself later in the day, alright? I don't have anything for you.
# 去附近找一下 看下有沒有
You can walk around and see if there's anything,
# 有沒有菜啊 有沒有那個
anything like veggies, or, you know.
# 有沒有菜啊 有沒有草根啊樹根之類的吃一下哦
anything like veggies, roots of grass, or tress, or whatever, as snacks.
# 幾天後
A few days later
# 摸你 快點 我給你搞癢癢 又不讓我抓子是不是
I just wanna touch you! C'mon, let me rub you! You don't like it now, do you?
# 給你抓癢癢哦 快點過來
Let me rub you. Come here!
# 來給你抓癢癢
Let me rub you!
# 現在不讓我
It doesn't like it now.
# 哎喲 哇 好兇啊
Ayo! Wa! It's so fierce!
# 養你那麼大 你竟然想吃我
I raise you up! But you wanna bite me!
# 出來出來出來
Come here, come here, come here!
# 給大家看一下你瘦了沒有
Let us see if you're getting skinny.
# 現在不讓人家摸了現在
Now it doesn't like my touch anymore.
# 給你揉一揉 要不要
I just rub, alright?
# 嘿嘿嘿 揉一下肚子就行了
Hehehe! Rubbing the belly is fine.
# 沒事 揉你肚子 以為我干嘛是不是 刀我都沒帶
No worries. I just rub your belly. Are you thinking that I'm gonna do something bad? I don't even have my knife with me!
# 真是的
Stupid piggy
# 揉了它肚子它自 它自己躺下
It lies, lies down by itself once I rub its belly.
# 爽不爽
Is it cool?
# 你喜歡大家摸你肚子是不是
You like it when I rub your belly, don't you?
# 不摸它它就自己躺下來 你看
It simply lies down by itself once I rub it, look!
# 在享受
It enjoys so much.
# 因為它肥肉太多了
It's because it has too much fat.
# 現在身材胖了一點點 所以
And now it's getting a bit fatter, so,
# 它被人家摸一下會舒服一點
it feels much better when I pet it.
# 剛剛你都想咬我是不是
He wanted to bite me a moment ago, didn't you?
# 我以為你變心了
I thought that you were no longer faithful to me.
# 原來還沒有變
But it's not the case.
# 如果你咬傷了我你就知道後果是怎麼樣子了
I'll show you the consequence if you really bite me.
# 你知不知道
Do you know what it is?
# 紅燒豬蹄
Stewed trotter
# 它是不是胃不舒服 我一摸它
Is the stomach hurting it? It comes,
# 它就 它就過來了
it comes to me every time, every time I touch it.
# 誒 它沒豬牙的 它的牙都好小
Eh? It has to tusks, but only smell teeth.
# 還是個 小豬豬
It's still a, little piggy.
# 波浪形
Rickrack
# 全身都在 全身的肉都在動
Every inch, every inch of skin is shaking.
# 好乖呦
It's such a good boy.
# 給你鬆鬆骨 按按摩 誒喲不肯了 是不是
Let me ease your weariness, give you a massage. Ayo! You don't like it, right?
# 拿這個前 前腿 做紅燒絕對好吃
This front, front leg, is absolutely tasty when it's stewed.
# 這個五花肉 這個應該是五花肉來的
This is pork belly. Here should be the pork belly.
# 小豬蹄
Tiny trotter
# 哎呀這 好多肉啊這裡
Aya! It's, it's so meaty here.
# 你看 它這 有點肥肉
Look! Here's, a little bit fat.
# 軟綿綿的這裡
It's as soft as a baby's bottom here.
# 它已經看破紅塵了
It has already seen through this mortal and materialistic world.
# 想吃飽就睡 睡飽就吃
So it simply sleeps after meals, and eats after waking up,
# 該吃的時候就吃 該喝的時候就喝 哦 是不是
eats when it's time to eat, and drinks when it's time to drink. Right?
# 好像它聽懂了 它說是
It seems that it understands. It says yes.
# 沒事的 是吧
No worries. Sure!
# 在這裡長 長大一點 長到五百斤去
You can grow here, grow bigger, up to two hundreds and fifty kilograms.
# 沒人說你
Nobody's gonna say anything.
# 一條豬
You are a pig.
# 保 保証把你養的肥肥胖胖
I pro, promise that I'll raise you up to a big fat pig.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦 這頭豬太會享受了
Alright! The video ends here. This pig enjoys its life so much.
# 你看 你的同伴有那麼享受嗎
Look! Is it a life that your companions can enjoy?
# 要是你的同伴這樣子呀 早就燒開水了
If they have anything, it's only the hot water waiting for them.
# 是不是 還不願意來我家
Am I right? But you still didn't want to come here.
# 這個豬刮毛的話 七 七八十度開水
Deharing this pig needs hot water of about seventy, seventy or eighty degrees.
# 不能 不能超過一百度 超過一百度就熟了
Never, never exceed a hundred degrees. Otherwise the pork would be cooked.
# 你看 這個豬還長了一根白毛 你看
Look! This pig has a white hair here, look!
# 它沒反應
No response.
# 你看 跟大白豬一樣的 白我
Look! It's like the big white pigs, white hair.
# 人工呼吸
Artificial respiration
# 不舒服了
It doesn't like it.
# 好啦好啦 走啦 我要幹活啦
Alright, alright! I gotta go now. I have to work.
# 自己找吃的啊
Get something to feed yourself, okay?
# 去找點樹根吃一下 樹皮吃一下
Feed yourself with some roots, or bark, or whatever.